# **TYLER SIMEONE**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

$\supset$	tyler.simeone@gmail.com
-----------	-------------------------

in /in/tylerpsimeone

(7) /tyler-simeone

🐧 (615)-715-3944

# **ABOUT ME**

I am a young, driven and goal-oriented student born in New York, but raised in Nashville, TN. When I'm not programming I enjoy spending time outdoors or learning new things that interest me. I am passionate about technology, innovation and growth.

I became aware of programming at a young age as my dad has been a programmer since the '80s. However, it wasn't until I took an online course that I realized programming was something that I would really enjoy doing as a career. I love working in teams and solving challenging problems to achieve goals.

# **PROJECTS**

### MTB CONNECT

- Web Application that allows users to search mountain bike trails by zip code and build a network of mountain biking friends that ride similar trails.
- I built this front-end app in three weeks using React.js with React State and React Hooks for displaying data and handling the user interface. CSS and Material UI for styling. As well as JSON Server with fetch requests for data storage and manipulation.
- <a href="https://github.com/tyler-simeone/MTB-connect">https://github.com/tyler-simeone/MTB-connect</a>

### FundsTracker

- Web app budgeting tool that helps users keep track of their income and expenses, as well as set financial goals for themselves.
- I Built this full-stack app using Django
  Templates and the ORM in order to fetch,
  manipulate, and deliver data from the
  database.
- https://github.com/tyler-simeone/FundsTracker

### **EDUCATION**

### Nashville Software School

Full-stack Web Development

### **Columbia State Community College**

Associate of Science Degree

# SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

### **Full-Stack Software Developer**

AUG 2019 - PRESENT

### Nashville Software School

Intensive full-time, full-stack software development course with an emphasis on individual and team-based projects.

Three months of remote learning and group project experience.

- Built front-end and full-stack web applications using JavaScript, React, Python, Django, SQL, HTML and CSS
- Utilized Git and GitHub for version control and issue tracking
- Utilized React State, Hooks, and Props to render data to the the front-end and handle the user interface
- Utilized Django REST framework to build APIs for full-stack applications

# **BANGAZON** - (Group Project)

- Full-stack Ecommerce application built with a team of 5, utilizing a React.js front-end and Django REST API back-end
- Individually responsible for implementing CRUD functionality for the user's payment methods, including implementation of Django Soft Delete
- Played integral role in assisting teammates with challenging roadblocks during the sprint

### **REACT NUTSHELL** - (Group Project)

- Multi-functional site built with a team of four that features news articles, local events, restaurants, and task lists
- Individually responsible for building React task components and API calls that allow the user to perform CRUD operations on their task list using JavaScript, React.js, Reactstrap and JSON Server

# WORK EXPERIENCE

### Franklin Water Store - Sales Associate

JUL 2018 - JUL 2019

Small business focused on producing and selling alkaline drinking water

 Developed a strong sense of teamwork and communication while working with a small team to help customers understand the benefits of alkaline water and water ionizing machines

### **Delivery Dudes** - Delivery Driver

APR 2015 - MAY 2018

- Grew strengths in detail and focus while fulfilling customer orders remotely from the Delivery Dudes headquarters using a proprietary web app
- Delivery driver where I optimized regular delivery routes to achieve more efficient order fulfillment times and increase productivity and sales during my shift